this is the part where we start making
这是我们开始制作的部分
our Donuts look sexy so uh we're going
我们的甜甜圈看起来很性感 所以我们要走了
to be coloring our sprinkles finally so
为我们的点缀上色 终于如此
it doesn't look so depressing um and
它看起来并不那么压抑 嗯 还有
then also getting into rendering to
然后还将介绍渲染到
start making this actually look pleasing
开始让这看起来很讨人喜欢
with Shadows and Light and everything
用阴影和光以及一切
else so first of all the sprinkles now
否则 首先要撒的是
as you probably know you could come in
正如你可能知道的 你可以进来
here and you could select a Sprinkle and
在这里 你可以选择一个洒水和
then go all right I'm going to make a a
那么走吧 好的 我要做一个
red sprinkle and then I'm going to don't
洒上红色 然后我就不会了
do this by the way I'm just showing you
按我刚才给你演示的方式来做
uh make this uh Aqua sprinkle
呃 把这个 呃 加点水
and then a blue sprinkle right and this
然后向右洒上蓝色的水 然后是这个
does work does exactly what you would
工作的效果和你想做的完全一样吗
expect the problem with this though is
不过 预计这方面的问题是
that for one the color is locked to that
其中之一就是颜色被锁定到那个
specific sprinkle so this curved
特定的洒水 所以这是弯曲的
sprinkle is always red okay and the
Sinkle总是红色的 好的
short sprinkle is always white the other
短洒水总是白的 另一个
issue is that this is not easy to change
问题是 这一点不容易改变
the distribution of those colors like if
这些颜色的分布 如IF
I'm an artist I'm looking this I'm like
我是个艺术家 我看起来就像这样
that's kind of boring because all the
这有点无聊 因为所有的
colors is like 25% blue 25% white 25 you
颜色相当于25%的蓝色25%的白色
know I want to have maybe 80% One uh
我知道我想要大概80%的
dominant color and then a few splashes
主色 然后是几滴水花
of complimentary colors I can't do that
免费赠送的颜色我做不到
so there is a much much easier way um so
所以有一种简单得多的方法
first let me just clear all of these and
首先 让我把所有这些都清理干净
I'm going to create one new material I'm
我要创作一种新材料
going to call it sprinkles and I'll
我会把它叫做撒布 然后我会
actually show you how to quickly apply
实际上向你展示了如何快速应用
uh the same material to multiple objects
呃 同一材料到多个物体上
at the same time um because we haven't
同时呢因为我们还没有
done that yet so let me I'm going to
做到了 所以让我来吧 我要
grab my round sprinkle which is
抓起我的圆形洒水
currently still over there by itself
目前还在那里独自一人
I'll just bring it over here so it's
我就把它拿过来 这样它就是
part of the family there we go all right
在那里我们是家庭的一部分 我们走得很好
so I've got uh I've got one object with
所以我有 呃 我有一个物体
the the material that I want to apply
我想要应用的材料
them all to uh what I need to do is
他们都是呃我需要做的是
shift select all the objects that I want
按住Shift键选择我需要的所有对象
to have that material and then lastly
拥有这种材料 然后最后
shift select again the object that has
再次按住Shift键选择具有
the material I want to apply them to and
我要将它们应用到的材质和
then and you know that cuz it's it's uh
然后 你知道 因为这是它是呃
highlighted yellow okay then hit contrl
突出显示黄色 确定 然后按Ctrl
l this brings up the link or transfer
L这是调出链接还是转接
menu and we want to link the
菜单 我们想要链接
materials and now you can see our
材料 现在您可以看到我们的
material has a five next to it because
材料旁边有一个5 因为
five material sorry five objects are
五件材料对不起五件物品是
sharing this material and that's it and
分享这些材料 仅此而已
now obviously because they're linked it
现在很明显因为他们把它联系在一起
means if I make a change over here um
意思是如果我在这里改变一下 嗯
they're all going to be reflected great
它们都会被很好地反映出来
now we're going to do something fancy so
现在我们要做一些奇特的事情
let's go to the shading tab which gives
让我们转到Shading选项卡 该选项卡提供
us access to our uh nodes oh dear where
我们可以访问我们的节点哦 天哪
have I all right let's go back trying to
我可以吗？让我们回去试着
get to that sprinkle okay to our uh
去到那个喷头 好吗 我们呃
notes now I want to introduce you to a
现在我想向你们介绍一位
little friend called shift a input the
小朋友叫Shift 是一种输入
object info node a very weird little uh
对象信息节点一个非常奇怪的小呢
weird little node that just does some
奇怪的小节点 只是做了一些
useful things when you might need it so
有用的东西 当你可能需要它的时候
you see it pop up in a few tutorials um
你会在几个教程中看到它 嗯
there's a bunch of stuff here that it
这里有一堆东西 它
can do the most useful one for us in
可以为我们做最有用的一件事
this instance is the random input drop
此实例是随机输入丢弃
that into your base color and let's see
变成你的底色 让我们看看
what happens so we've got some gray
会发生什么 所以我们有一些灰色的
values and it's easier to see actually
价值 而且实际上更容易看到
when you look at the donuts so what this
当你看着甜甜圈时 这是什么
has done is it has assigned a value a
所做的是将一个值赋值为
random value for each individual
每个人的随机值
sprinkle between zero and one so because
散布在0和1之间是因为
that's then being transferred to color
然后被转移到颜色上
information it means that for example
信息它意味着 例如
this sprinkle might have got a value of
这一点可能会值到
like
喜欢
0.0 2 3 right the robot spat that out uh
0.02 3对了 机器人把它吐出来了
and then this one this white is look one
然后这个白色的看起来像一个
maybe this was
也许这就是
0.89 or something like that okay so it's
0.89或类似的东西 好的 所以
just transferred those values into color
只需将这些值转换为颜色
information which is just blacks to
仅供黑人查看的信息
whites not very useful right now but we
白人现在不是很有用 但我们
can use that those those numbers in a
可以使用这些数字在一个
I'll just show you okay shift a we're
我给你演示一下 好的 轮班a 我们
going to go converter color ramp
要转到转换器色带
probably I mean I might have used this
可能我的意思是我可能用了这个
node more than any other node in blender
搅拌机中的节点比任何其他节点都多
before it's like so versatile used for
在它如此多才多艺之前
so many things so drop it in here
这么多的东西 所以把它放在这里
between the object info and the
在对象信息和
principled and uh currently it is
原则性的 呃目前是
exactly the same because it's just the
完全一样 因为它只是
it's transferring that data into a
它正在将数据传输到一个
gradient value of the exact same Shades
完全相同色调的渐变值
but we can change
但我们可以改变
this to any color that we want and look
这是我们想要和看起来的任何颜色
at that so you can very quickly see this
这样你就可以很快地看到这个
is exactly how we're going to create
就是我们将如何创造
sprinkles of different colors um now one
洒上不同的颜色 嗯 现在是一个了
thing you'll note looking at this is
看到这个你会注意到的是
that every single sprinkle is a
每一滴水都是
different shade like no two sprinkles
不同的色调就像没有两个花洒
have the same color right now because
现在有相同的颜色 因为
this is a gradient and that's not how it
这是一种渐变 不是这样的
works in the real world because the
在现实世界中工作 因为
sprinkles come out of you know one
洒出来的水你知道吗？
constant icing bag right or a machine
恒定冰袋对还是机器？
with the same food di so basically all
用同样的食物 所以基本上都是
the blue ones would have the exact shade
蓝色的会有完全一样的色调
of blue and all the orange ones would
蓝色和所有橙色的都会
have the exact shade orange so we need
有和橙色一模一样的 所以我们需要
to change this from linear to constant
将其从线性更改为常量
and now if I slide this across look at
现在如果我把这个放到另一边 看看
that we are influencing what percentage
我们正在影响的百分比
now is orange or blue and this is really
现在是橙色或蓝色 这真的是
cool cuz it means you get to work like
酷 因为这意味着你可以像
an artist and just create a really nice
一位艺术家 只是创造了一个非常好的
appealing looking donut very very
看起来很吸引人 非常非常
quickly so I'm going to go with like a
很快 所以我要用一种
light blue over here and then I'm going
这里是浅蓝色的 然后我要走了
to create a new color just by hitting
只需点击即可创建新颜色
the plus button and then let's give this
加号按钮 然后让我们给出这个
a purple like that and I'll make this
像那样的紫色 我会做这个
one pink actually same shade as our dut
一种粉色实际上和我们的DUT颜色一样
why not you'll note by the way that I'm
为什么不呢？顺便说一句你会注意到我
not going like full saturation um and
不是完全饱和 嗯 还有
that's deliberate because you learn in
这是故意的 因为你在
our that yeah like saturation and color
我们的那个 是的 像饱和度和色彩
is quite uh aggressive it's quite noisy
很有攻击性 很吵
and uh quite attention grabbing and so
而且 呃 相当吸引眼球 所以
if you use too much of it it can be
如果你用得太多 可能会
exhausting so I I tend to keep it at
精疲力尽 所以我我倾向于保持在
like
喜欢
08 um okay and then I'll also go over
嗯 好的 然后我也会过去的
here and I'm going to make this white
在这里 我要把它变成白色
let's go oh whoop no not like that white
我们走吧 哦 不 不像那个白色的
and I'm going to create another one next
接下来 我将创建另一个
to it and this one I'm going to make
对于它和我要做的这一个
yellow okay so just by sliding this
黄色 好的 只要滑动这个
around I could say like less white more
在我周围 我可以说少一些白色 多一些
yellow less yellow more white and then I
黄色少了黄色多了白色然后我
can go yeah more blue it's just a really
可以走得更蓝 这只是一个真正的
simple easy way to create the exact um
简单、容易的方法来创建精确的um
the exact look you're going for awesome
你想要的样子太棒了
now something uh you don't have to do
现在 呃 一些你不需要做的事情
this next part but it's so easy why not
这是下一部分 但这很容易 为什么不呢
I was looking on a Pinterest on like uh
我在看Pinterest 就像这样
like aesthetically pleasing Donuts like
就像美观的甜甜圈一样
trying to make this uh look really cool
试着让这个呃看起来很酷
and uh and I saw like metallic sprinkles
然后我看到了像金属碎片一样的
and I was like hm that's an interesting
我就想 这很有趣
idea what if I made these white and
如果我把这些做成白色和
yellow ones metallic and then they would
黄色的是金属的 然后他们会
look silver and gold so there is a
看着银色和金色 所以有一个
slider in your principled bsdf technical
滑块在您的原则性BSDF技术
name that just means it's the Shader
这只意味着它是着色器
that does everything um and it's the
它做了所有的事情 嗯 这是
metallic Shader look at that so if I
金属着色器看看这个 如果我
slide this all the way to one all my
把这个一直滑到一个 我的
sprinkles are now metallic and if I
喷洒现在是金属的 如果我
slide all the way to zero then they are
一路滑落到零然后他们就是
non-metallic and that's actually how you
非金属 这实际上就是你如何
should use this slider all materials in
应使用此滑块中的所有材质
the real world are either uh
现实世界要么是呃
non-metallic also known as dialectric
非金属材料 也称为辩证法
materials so that would be most of the
材料 所以这将是大多数
sprinkles um and then some objects are
洒上这个 然后一些物体
metallic entirely metallic um there are
金属的 全金属的 嗯 有
technically a few rare materials on
从技术上讲 几种稀有材料
Earth that have some blend between it
地球之间有一些交融
but as a rule you should not have a
但一般来说 你不应该有一个
value that is between zero and one it
值 该值介于0和1之间
should be either zero or one anyways so
无论如何 应该是0或1
what we can do with this because we've
我们可以用这个做什么 因为我们已经
got this color ramp information here is
这里得到的色带信息是
I can actually uh just convert like I
我其实可以 呃 就像我
can make a color ramp that is just black
可以制作出黑色的色带
and white that just shows which sprinkle
和白色 这只是显示哪一种洒
is metallic and which one isn't so um if
是金属的 哪一个不是 嗯 如果
I duplicate this and here's a pro tip if
我复制了这个 这是一个专业的提示 如果
you use control shift d it will
您使用Ctrl Shift d它将会
duplicate it but it will retain its
复制它 但它将保留其
connection so just saves you I don't
连接 所以只是救了你 我不
know one second uh and now I'm going to
知道一秒钟 嗯 现在我要
connect that into my metallic input now
现在把它连接到我的金属输入端上
currently this is wrong because this
目前这是错误的 因为这
information is uh it's just using yeah
信息是 呃 它只是在使用 是的
it's like color so we need to be black
它就像颜色 所以我们需要是黑色的
and white so this one here because this
白色 所以这一张是因为这张
is going to represent my dialectric
将代表我的辩证法
colors I'm going to set this to Black so
颜色我要将其设置为黑色 所以
it is non-metal and then this I can
它是非金属的 然后这个我可以
delete and this I can delete because
删除 这个我可以删除 因为
because on the left hand side of it it's
因为在它的左手边
all black sorry so it's all uh
都是黑色的 对不起 所以都是呃
non-metals and then over here these two
非金属材料 然后这里是这两个
the uh the silver and the gold they're
呃 银子和金子 他们是
going to be metal so actually I can
会变成金属 所以实际上我可以
delete the gold and now that's doing
删除黄金 现在就是这样做了
exactly what it should so we've now got
这正是它应该做的 所以我们现在有了
dialectric non-metals and metals and the
非金属与金属的辩证关系
reason it doesn't look like metal by the
因为它看起来不像金属
way is cuz your roughness is here so if
方法是因为你的粗糙在这里 所以如果
you set it all the way down you can see
你把它一直往下放 你就能看到
it starts to look a lot closer to a
它开始看起来更接近于
metallic
金属化
sprinkle um and by the way you can get
撒上这个 顺便说一句 你可以
the exact like position you can go like
一模一样的姿势 你可以像
7 and then here 7 type it in and then
7然后在这里7键入 然后
that way it's definitely uh correct for
那样的话肯定是呃正确的
whatever reason of mine this has to be a
不管是我的原因 这肯定是
bug there's something weird about it but
Bug 这有点奇怪 但是
there's one sprinkle on my Donuts
我的甜甜圈上洒了一滴
probably not on yours but it's like it's
可能不是你的 但就像是
it's it's purple up here but then it
这上面是紫色的 但它
crept over into the metallic category
悄悄地进入了金属类别
down here which shouldn't be possible
在这里 这是不可能的
but evidently it's just on my I've never
但很明显 它就在我身上 我从来没有
seen it before but one of them has
以前见过 但其中一人见过
actually snuck over doesn't matter it's
其实偷偷溜过来并不重要
a what it it can be the rare purple uh
A它是什么它可以是稀有的紫色呢
metallic One um all right but I don't
金属的 嗯 好的 但我不
want the uh these other ones to be uh
我想要呃这些其他的
shiny at least that shiny so I'm going
闪闪发光 至少有那么闪亮 所以我要走了
to again duplicate this control shift d
要再次复制此控制Shift d
and with this if I plug this into my
如果我把这个插到我的
roughness input just like before these
粗糙度输入就像之前的这些
black and white values will decide what
黑人和白人的价值观将决定
is the roughness of the metallic and non
是金属和非金属的粗糙度
non-metallics so this one here um I want
非金属的 所以这个 嗯 我想要
this to be essentially the opposite of
这在本质上是与
what it is almost entirely black a
它几乎完全是黑色的
little bit so that there's a little bit
一点 所以有一点
of roughness to it like that and then
像这样的粗糙 然后
this one over here I want this to be a
这个在这里 我希望这是一个
lot more diffuse not entirely diffuse
更多的漫射而不是完全漫射
like somewhat of a blend cuz if you look
就像是一种混合体 如果你看起来
at reference which you should be
在你应该被引用的地方
modeling off reference there is uh some
模特儿参考 呃 有一些
shininess to them so yeah but that is it
对他们来说闪闪发光 所以是的 但就是这样
so you can see very quickly we have
所以你们可以很快看到我们有
created some very aesthetically pleasing
创造了一些非常美观的东西
donuts and have fun with it guys like
甜甜圈 玩得开心 就像
create a cool looking donut um you can
创造一个看起来很酷的甜甜圈
use whatever color combinations you you
使用任何你喜欢的颜色组合
want I really do like it when people
我真的很喜欢当人们
experiment and not just follow a
实验 而不是简单地遵循
tutorial down to a tea but like venture
教程归根结底是一杯茶 但喜欢冒险
out there and you know do do interesting
在那里 你知道做一些有趣的事情
things so try different color
所以试一试不同的颜色
combinations try different icing colors
组合尝试不同的冰雪颜色
um and you could make something that
嗯 你可以做一些东西
looks uh looks really cool but that's
看起来 呃 看起来真的很酷 但那
almost it for our donut it's pretty well
差不多是我们的甜甜圈了 挺好的
done which means we can now finally talk
完成了 这意味着我们现在终于可以谈谈了
about rendering so as a recap of uh of
关于渲染的内容 作为对
part one if you hit F12 that's going to
第一部分如果你按下F12键 就会
put you into the rendered state our
将您置于我们的呈现状态
camera is really far away from the donut
相机离甜甜圈真的很远
so actually let's first fix that if you
所以实际上我们先解决这个问题 如果你
go to your camera view you just by
打开你的相机 只需
clicking that little icon there or by
点击那里的小图标或通过
hitting number pad uh zero that'll take
敲击数字键盘 呃 零 这将需要
you there as well um this is the camera
你也在那里 嗯 这是摄像机
view we're really far away I mentioned
我们真的很远 我提到过
in the start that uh if you use uh this
在开始的时候 如果你用这个
key this button view lock camera to view
按此键查看锁定摄像头即可查看
that'll let you like grab it and move it
这会让你喜欢抓起它并移动它
around but it is actually another way I
但这实际上是我的另一种方式
didn't want to introduce you to too many
我不想给你介绍太多
uh keyboard shortcuts at the start but
一开始的键盘快捷键 但是
if you hit with the camera selected
如果您在选择相机的情况下击球
shift Tilla key that will put you in fly
Shift Tilla键可以让你飞起来
mode uh the other way to do that by the
模式 呃 另一种方式 通过
way is to just go uh view navigation fly
方法就是去 呃 看导航飞行
navigation there if you don't have that
如果你没有的话 你可以在那里导航
key so anyway in this mode it's now it's
所以不管怎样 在这种模式下 现在是
almost like you're playing a video game
就像你在玩电子游戏一样
so like it's just I'm playing a
所以就像我只是在扮演一个
first-person shooter looking around my
第一人称射手环顾我的
scene w is move forward just like in a
场景w正在向前移动 就像在
video game uh a is strafe left D is
电子游戏呃A是左撇子D是
strafe right and S is back so w ASD just
右截击 S回来了 所以我们只是
like a video game um I can also go up by
就像电子游戏一样 嗯 我也可以
hitting e and then down by hitting q and
按下e 然后按下q和
if it's too sensitive like if the
如果它太敏感了 比如
movement is like you know crazy fast uh
运动就像你知道的疯狂的快
the scroll wheel also decides how uh far
滚轮还决定了呃距离
oh goodness there it is okay how fast
哦 天哪 好的 多快？
the movement is so scroll down if it's
运动是如此向下滚动 如果它是
going too quickly for you um but yeah I
对你来说太快了 但是 是的 我
can now place place the camera wherever
现在可以随时随地放置摄像头
it is I want and then when it's there I
这是我想要的 当它在那里的时候
just click single left click and now
只需单击鼠标左键即可
it's there and by the way that mode is H
它就在那里 顺便说一下 那个模式是H
called fly navigation and it works also
它被称为飞行导航 它也能工作
not just from the camera view but
不仅是从摄像机的角度来看 而且
anywhere in blender if you ever want to
在搅拌机的任何地方 如果你想
just like you know move around you can
就像你知道的那样 你可以四处走动
do uh use that fly mode so shift tilter
有没有使用飞行模式所以换档倾斜
key for that all right so we do a render
关键字 好的 所以我们进行渲染
we get something that looks hideous why
我们得到了一些看起来很可怕的东西为什么
is that well for starters it's not a
对于初学者来说这是好事吗？这不是
very the scene has just got one light in
场景中只有一盏灯亮了进来
it but the primary reason and by the way
这只是主要原因 顺便说一句
uh the yes that's the render View mode
呃 是的 这是渲染视图模式
but also if you go to rendered view
而且如果您转到渲染视图
shading up there this is the exact
遮挡在那里这就是
replica of that but just in the viewport
它的复制品 但仅在视口中
okay
好吧
now the primary reason this looks bad is
现在看起来很糟糕的主要原因是
because of the renderer okay so
因为渲染器 好的 所以
blender's default render engine if you
搅拌器的默认渲染引擎 如果
go to your render properties is called
转到您的渲染属性称为
EV now EV is fast but it is not accurate
现在的电动汽车速度很快 但并不准确
if you are familiar with games most of
如果你熟悉大部分的游戏
you probably are um EV is basically a
你可能是 嗯 电动汽车基本上是一个
game engine so it's designed to be
游戏引擎 所以它被设计成
really fast probably not 60 frames per
真的很快 可能不是每帧60帧
second but really really fast um and
第二 但真的很快 嗯 还有
it's a in terms of uh the renderer types
就渲染器类型而言 这是一个
there's usually actually you call them
通常情况下你会给他们打电话
like real time is what this type is and
就像实时就是这种类型
that is a rasterized uh render engine
这是一个光栅化的呃渲染引擎
and then you have Ray Tred or path
然后你有了光线树或路径
traced engine sometimes called offline
跟踪引擎有时称为脱机
renderers um which are a lot more
渲染器 嗯 更多的
accurate but much slower so this is good
准确 但速度慢得多 所以这很好
if you don't really care about realism
如果你真的不关心现实主义
uh like maybe you're making a title
呃 就像你在做一个头衔
effect for a TV you know thing or
对电视的影响你知道的事情还是
whatever or you're on a really tight
不管怎么说 否则你就会手头紧绷
deadline you just want to get something
截止日期你只想得到一些东西
out fast you can use EV um now you can
快点出来 你可以使用EV 嗯 现在你可以
make it look better than what we have
让它看起来比我们现有的更好
like for example I think the because
比如 我认为是因为
we're using like really small sizes for
我们使用的是非常小的尺码
our donut you want to increase your Cube
我们的甜甜圈你想增加你的立方体
size and then your lamp the bias there
大小 然后你的灯的偏置在那里
you go you set that all the way to zero
你去 你把它一直设置为零
um and now it's more appropriate for
嗯 现在它更适合于
this size we've got Shadows but it's
这个尺码我们有影子 但它是
still not great um we don't for example
仍然不是很好 嗯 我们不是很好
have shadows on any of our sprinkles um
有阴影在我们的任何散布上 嗯
because it's just too fine a detail and
因为这个细节太细腻了
the shadow itself it's just like a
阴影本身它就像一个
blurry mess so this is it's just a
一团糟 所以这只是一场
fakery um and it's just like what's
造假 嗯 就像是什么
going on uh with with video games I will
继续玩电子游戏 我会的
briefly mention also that blunder 4.1
也简单地提到那个错误4.1
which is what this is here it's in Alpha
这就是这个 它是阿尔法的
State at the time of this recording I've
在录制这段录音的时候 我已经
been using 4.0 for the this whole
我一直在使用4.0作为这个整体
recording but this is 4.1 and it is a
录音 但这是4.1 这是一个
it's EV but it's completely Rewritten
它是电动汽车 但它被完全重写了
and it is better right so the Shadows
而且这样更好 所以影子
are better um there is actually even
是不是更好 嗯 实际上甚至
some bounce lighting happening but it's
一些反弹的灯光正在发生 但它
kind of like a fake bounce lighting and
有点像一个假的反弹灯光和
it's definitely better but it's still
它当然更好 但它仍然是
not
不
great so that is the limitation it's
太好了 这就是它的局限性
fast but it is not great um and that's
很快 但不是很好 嗯 那是
what you get with rasterized real time
实时栅格化后的效果
um engines so there is another render
UM引擎 所以有另一个渲染
engine to go to your render engine
引擎转到您的渲染引擎
settings and click the drop down ignore
设置 然后单击忽略下拉菜单
workbench that's for like um just like
工作台 就像 嗯 就像
basically rendering your viewport really
基本上是渲染您的视区
for technical stuff um Cycles so those
对于技术方面的东西 嗯周期 所以那些
are the two main engines of of blender
是搅拌机的两个主要引擎
you got cycles and you've got EV Cycles
你有循环 你有电动汽车循环
is uh what's known as an offline
就是所谓的离线
renderer or a path trade also known as
渲染器或路径交易 也称为
Ray traced engine now uh this looks way
光线追踪引擎现在 呃 看起来是这样的
better than what we had before you'll
比我们以前拥有的更好你会
notice for example that all of our
请注意 例如 我们所有的
sprinkles have shadows by the way
顺便说一句 洒水有阴影
apologies if my recording gets a little
如果我的录音有一点小问题 很抱歉
choppy it's because it's uh using the
波涛汹涌 因为它 呃 正在使用
CPU anyway um you can see it's uh it's
无论如何 CPU 嗯 你可以看到它 呃 它是
got proper Shadows on things uh there's
在事情上有适当的阴影 呃 有
actually bounce lighting right that's
实际上反射光线是正确的 这是
like coming off this uh this table here
就像从这张呃这张桌子上下来
and it's going underneath the dut um so
它在垃圾堆下面 嗯 所以
it's like it's shooting around inside
就像它在里面四处飞舞
here and it's shooting back and it's
在这里 它正在反击 它是
going over here which is exactly what
到这里来 这就是
happens in the real world and it's
发生在现实世界中 这是
really important for realism to get that
对于现实主义来说 理解这一点真的很重要
uh bounce I mean any room any
呃 弹跳 我是说任何房间
architecture you basically have to use
您基本上必须使用的架构
Cycles um to do it because uh that's how
循环 嗯 因为这就是为什么
you get proper lighting like in the real
你可以得到真实的灯光效果
world but you get all this for free at
世界上所有这些都是免费的
the cost of speed so you'll notice as I
速度的代价 所以你会注意到我
move around whilst my recording goes
在我录音的时候四处走动
choppy that it's starts grainy and then
起伏不定 开始是颗粒状的 然后
it kind of refines itself and if you
它会自我完善 如果你
look in the top leftand Corner you've
看看左上角 你已经
got something that says says samples so
我拿到的东西上写着样品是这样的
uh as you leave it uh rendering longer
呃 当你把它呃渲染得更长的时候
it's rendering more samples essentially
它本质上渲染了更多的样本
it's just like the computer's just
就像电脑就像是
chewing through it that's I mean it
咬穿它 我是认真的
there's technical ways to explain it but
有一些技术方法可以解释它 但
that's the simplest way to think of it
这是最简单的思考方式
and it'll get clearer as uh the longer
随着时间的延长 它会变得更加清晰
you leave it now there is actually two
你现在离开它 实际上有两个
ways to calculate this one is to use
计算这个值的方法是使用
your CPU which is what it's on by
您的CPU 这就是它所在的位置
default another is to use your GPU which
默认情况下 另一种是使用您的GPU
is grade out by default so let's fix
默认情况下是分级的 所以我们来修正一下
that go to edit preferences and then go
进入编辑首选项 然后继续
to system and you can see at the top
到系统 您可以在顶部看到
there Cycles Render devices so try
有渲染设备的周期 所以请尝试
switching to one of these tabs and see
切换到这些选项卡中的一个并查看
what you get if you have a device like
如果你有一个像这样的设备 你会得到什么
myself uh that is a GPU that is
我自己呢 那是一个图形处理器
supported um then you can render on that
支持的 嗯 然后您可以在上面渲染
and it'll be way faster so just as an
而且它会更快 所以就像
FYI Cuda is NVIDIA and it's for like
FYI Cuda是NVIDIA 它的意思是
cards like I think 1080 backwards so
像我想的1080张这样的牌
like 90s 800s I think they used CA
就像90年代的800 我想他们用的是CA
Optics was around uh the 2,000 series um
光学在 呃 2000系列 嗯
further on so Optics is the one that you
再往前看 光学公司就是你
use if you're using a ninia card today
如果您现在使用的是尼尼亚卡 请使用
uh hip is for AMD cards and then you got
HIP是用于AMD卡的 然后你就有了
one API and I think actually on Apple
一个API和我认为实际上是在Apple上
devices you'll have a metal option but
设备您将有一个金属选项 但
see what you have and then see if you
看看你有什么 然后看看你是否
can render with that because that with
可以用它来渲染 因为用它
GPU on now it'll uh go back to this it
打开图形处理器现在它将呃返回到这个它
might actually the first time you use
可能实际上是你第一次使用
your GPU it will say I think at the top
你的图形处理器会说我认为在顶端
leftand corner um doing this for the
LeftAnd Corner Um为
first time it'll do some pass it'll be
第一次它会做一些传球它会
really slow it might take like 2 minutes
真的很慢 可能需要2分钟
but then after you've done that every
但在你做完这些之后
time you open blender you should never
当你打开搅拌机时 你永远不应该
need to do it again so it might be slow
需要再做一次 这样可能会很慢
the first time you activate it but it'll
你第一次激活它 但它会
um it should be faster now this is way
嗯 现在应该快点了 就是这样
faster than what we had before like you
比我们以前像你一样的速度更快
can see how quickly it's uh it's
可以看到它有多快 呃 它是
clearing through those samples um it's
清理那些样品 嗯 这是
basically real time um it's uh in fact
基本上是实时的 嗯 事实上
actually so that noise that I mentioned
实际上 我提到的那个噪音
right it's still there but when you
是的 它还在那里 但当你
render and also in your viewport you can
渲染 也可以在您的视区中
use a denoiser so it's uh it's actually
使用消噪器 所以它是 呃 实际上
not that new it's like 3 four years old
不是很新 好像有3到4年了
I think we started using Aid noises um
我想我们开始使用辅助噪音 嗯
Nvidia released their one for Optics um
NVIDIA发布了One for Optics Um
and since then Intel have come out with
从那时起 英特尔就推出了
one and it basically takes that noisy
一辆 基本上就是这么吵
image it uses some of the information
图像它使用了一些信息
from the 3D renderer to clear it out
从3D渲染器中清除它
whilst preserving the detail so if you
在保留细节的同时 如果您
can actually turn it on in the viewport
实际上可以在视口中将其打开
by hitting the dno one if you've got a
如果你有一个DNO的话
Nvidia card it'll be way better if you
NVIDIA卡 如果你能
don't it'll have to use the Intel
不是吗？它必须使用情报
denoiser which is a lot slower um but
去噪速度慢了很多 嗯 但是
you can see the noise is practically
你可以看到噪音几乎是
gone right so this is almost real time
正确 所以这几乎是实时的
um which is really really cool now
嗯 现在真的很酷
obviously not all of you are as lucky
显然 并不是你们所有人都这么幸运
right I've got four
好的 我有四个
309s um I started though on a Pentium 3
309 嗯 我是从奔腾3开始的
I think back in 2003 um and I mean look
我回想起2003年 嗯 我是说
they made a Toy Story on computers that
他们在电脑上制作了一个玩具故事
you couldn't even sell today cuz they
你今天甚至卖不出去 因为他们
would be just garbage maybe you could
只会是垃圾也许你可以
for like nostalgic anyways the point is
因为不管怎么说 像怀旧一样 重点是
is that everybody when they start 3D is
当他们开始3D时 每个人都是
using a device which is crappy don't let
使用一个糟糕的设备 不要让
it limit you or don't think oh I can't
它限制了你 或者不认为 哦 我不能
use 3D until I get a better
使用3D 直到我得到更好的
computer a graphics card is definitely
电脑一块显卡绝对是
one of the best investments you can make
你能做的最好的投资之一
if you're thinking like I want to do
如果你的想法和我想的一样
this as a career this is definitely for
这是一份职业 这绝对是为了
me I'm really enjoying this um it's
我 我真的很喜欢这个 嗯 这是
definitely a good investment because you
绝对是一项不错的投资 因为你
will be able to uh produce more renders
将能够呃生成更多的渲染
throughout the day faster um but it is
一整天都更快 嗯 但它是
not essential you can get by with just a
不是必须的 你只需要一个
CPU it just means that when you do your
它只是意味着当你做你的
render your final render instead of it
渲染您的最终渲染而不是它
being you know done in an hour you might
你知道在一个小时内完成 你可能会
have to leave it overnight um in the
必须把它放在隔夜 嗯 放在
past when I started with blender I was
过去 当我开始使用搅拌机时 我
making crappy renders at like 600 by 400
制作糟糕的渲染效果类似于600 x 400
resolution and I was rendering for over
分辨率和我已经渲染了很久
a week just to do a really crappy basic
一周就是为了做一个很烂的基础
animation so don't let it hinder you
动漫 所以不要让它阻碍你
it's it's totally normal that you'll
这是完全正常的 你会
have a bad computer um if it's for you
电脑坏了 嗯 如果是给你的
in the future definitely worth investing
在未来绝对值得投资
in in um in a card that is fast also if
在这个卡里 快的也是如果
you want to know which card to buy uh
你想知道买哪张卡呢
blender actually put together an open
搅拌机实际上组装了一个开放的
Benchmark uh so if you go to open dat.
基准 嗯 所以如果你去打开dat.
blender.org or click the link in the
.org或单击链接中的
description you can see it's showing you
你可以看到它正在向你展示的描述
all of the the people that have done
所有的人都做了
this Benchmark what have their devices
这个基准测试有他们的设备
been and what are the times that you can
去过了 什么时候你可以
expect so you can see as see mine is at
期待 这样你就能看到 就像我的一样
the bottom it's the uh 3090 uh but it's
底部是呃3090 但它是
I've got four of them so it's it's
我有四个 所以就是这样
obviously turning through it faster the
显然 更快地翻阅它
fastest is I mean basically it's going
最快的是我的意思是基本上它在
to be the top card or like the go-to
成为最好的牌或喜欢去的人
Nvidia is just crushing it um I think uh
NVIDIA正在摧毁它 嗯 我想嗯
where is the AMD they used to be on I
他们曾经服用的AMD在哪里？
think AMD is made a made a mention there
我想AMD在那里提了一下
you've also got CPUs on this side but
这一端也有CPU 但是
essentially I mean just by the top like
从本质上说 我的意思是 就像
gaming card usually that's the one um
游戏卡通常就是这张
but do go here check it out if you want
不过 如果你想的话 一定要去这里看看
all right so we're going to be using
好的 所以我们将使用
cycles for the rest of this tutorial um
循环用于本教程的其余部分
and we'll really dive into it in the
我们将真正深入到
next part but I just want to quickly um
下一部分 但我只想快点嗯
my lamp is way way away so let's just
我的灯很远 所以我们就
bring that in closer just so that we can
把它拉近一点 这样我们就可以
see things and you can actually clear
看到一些东西 你实际上可以清楚地看到
the rotation of an object to make it
使物体旋转以使其
appear at the the center of your 3D
显示在3D的中心
scene by tapping alt G okay so now hey
点击Alt G的场景好的 那么现在嘿
look that's actually kind of cool um I'm
听着 这其实挺酷的 嗯 我
going to move uh my lamp over to here
我要把我的台灯搬到这里来
just check my recordings yeah my
查一下我的录音是的我的
recording is not being affected um and
录制没有受到影响 嗯
I'll just now reduce the strength of
我现在要减少的力量
this because it's obviously now way
因为这显然是现在的方式
closer but look at that like look at the
更近一点 但看起来就像看着
shadow that we get um coming off this
我们得到的阴影 嗯 从这个开始
donut um it's like properly taped it's
甜甜圈 嗯 就像被正确地粘好了一样
not like some fakery so it's like tight
不像是假的 所以它很紧
here and then it's like really uh faded
时不时地 它就像真的 呃 褪色了
at the end there that kind of stuff is
在最后 这类东西是
really difficult to do with a um a a
真的很难用一个嗯a a a
rasterized realtime engine like EV uh
像EV这样的光栅化实时引擎
and you also get like all of this proper
你也会得到所有这些适当的
like look at the Shadows on the
就像看着天空中的影子
sprinkles the reflections is actually
洒下的倒影实际上是
true it's not like guessing and fakery
的确 这不像猜测和伪造
um yes it's a type of fakery but it's
嗯 是的 这是一种造假 但它是
it's much more accurate um anyways I I
它更准确 嗯 不管怎么说 我
like Cycles I'm I'm A Cycles guy um I
喜欢自行车 我是自行车爱好者 嗯 我
think most people actually are the first
我认为大多数人实际上是第一个
version of Eevee was not that great
Eevee的版本并没有那么棒
Eevee next in 4.1 might be better we'll
Eevee Next in 4.1可能会更好
see uh but yeah the first version of
看 呃 但是 是的 第一个版本
Eevee was not really that great now one
埃维现在已经不是很棒了
thing you might notice looking at your D
你可能会注意到的东西 看着你的D
I'm going to make one one big tweak to
我要做一个很大的调整来
this is that it kind of feels hard like
这就是说 感觉很难
doesn't give this kind of like soft
不会给人一种柔软的感觉
feeling to it and the reason for that is
对它的感觉 其原因是
the material so by default all materials
材料 因此默认情况下所有材料
are yeah kind of like hard materials but
是的有点像硬材料 但是
fleshy objects like humans as well as
像人类这样的肉体物体
food have subsurf for scattering so I'll
食物有散落的潜水 所以我会
throw some reference photos here um but
在这里扔一些参考照片 嗯 但是
you can see this is my hand I had uh
你可以看到这是我的手我曾经呃
light coming in like as I was eating
当我吃东西的时候 光线进来了
breakfast and I can see the light is
早餐和我能看到的光是
actually going through my fingers right
实际上是从我的手指间穿过
so that's light that is uh like yeah
所以这就是光 呃 就像是的
it's a mushy fleshy object so it's
它是一个黏糊糊的肉质物体 所以它
passing through it scattering amongst
穿过它 散布在
all the other atoms in the finger and
手指中的所有其他原子和
it's uh the light is going through to
它是 呃 光线正在穿过到
the other side you also see it um in a
另一方面 你也看到了 嗯 在一个
lot of food so took these photos at a
很多食物 所以在一个
party yes I am that guy U but you can
派对是的 我就是那个你 但你可以
see that's how you get light that goes
看 这就是你获得光明的方式
uh to the opposite sides uh my daughter
呃 在对面 呃 我的女儿
was eating a banana and uh I was like
在吃香蕉 呃 我就像
look at that banana look at that
看那个香蕉看那个
subsurface scattering right there so
地下散射就在那里 所以
donuts and icing have that and we can do
甜甜圈和糖霜有这一点 我们可以做到
that we can add that sorry by going to
我们可以通过转到
the materials and then down here you've
材料 然后在这里 你有
got subsurface okay so here uh the the
得到了地下的好的 所以在这里 呃
biggest one to turn it on and just like
最大的一个 就像
metallic apparently this is uh by the
很明显 这是呃由
way a new setup for 4.0 but just like
这是4.0的新设置 但就像
metallic it's supposed to be a weight of
金属 它应该是一个重量的
either zero or one all right now when
要么是0 要么是1好的 当
you do one it suddenly turned blue and
你做了一次 它突然变蓝了
you're like what the hell happened there
你就像地狱里发生的事一样
that's because the radius this uh radius
那是因为这个半径 这个半径
is uh it's this is your XY Z but also
是 呃 这是你的XY Z 而且
it's your RG and your B in this case and
在这种情况下是你的RG和你的B
these values are different because it's
这些值不同 因为它是
designed for skin by default so this is
默认情况下是为皮肤设计的 因此这是
a great setup if you've got skin with
一个很棒的设置 如果你有皮肤的话
blood inside but we don't so click drag
里面有血 但我们没有 所以点击拖拽
down and then just set these values to
然后将这些值设置为
one all right so now it's closer to the
好的 所以现在它更接近
material still looks weird and that's
材料看起来仍然很奇怪 那是
cuz the scale of this is wrong it's
因为这件事的规模是错误的
saying that the thickness of the object
也就是说物体的厚度
is 5 cm but this icing is not that so
是5厘米 但这个糖衣不是这样的
let's make this
让我们做这件事
01 and now you can see it looks a lot
01 现在你可以看到它看起来很多
closer it's still a little dark so I
再近一点 天还是有点黑 所以我
think it's uh it's not 1 cm thick so
我想它呃它不是1厘米厚所以
let's go
我们走吧
0.5 and now we can see it's pretty close
0.5 现在我们可以看到它非常接近
to its original
恢复到原来的样子
material the biggest difference is if I
材料最大的区别是如果我
just zoom right in here let's set it to
只要放大这里 让我们将其设置为
what it was before see how it's hard it
它以前是什么 看它有多难
almost feels like uh it just feels like
感觉就像 呃 就像是
concrete right but then you set this to
混凝土是正确的 但随后您将其设置为
one and look at that the the shadow just
一看 那个影子刚刚
starts to feel a little softer and you
开始感觉有点柔和 而你
get this bleed effect where kind of like
得到这个流血效果 就像
the shadow gets a like an edge to the
阴影变得像一个边缘到
shadow where it gets a little more
阴影在哪里变得更多
saturated and Pinker um and that's Subs
饱和的和粉色的 嗯 那是Subs
surface scattering you don't have to
表面散射 你不需要
tell it how to do that it just does it
告诉它怎么做 它就会去做
so you set the weight to one these to
因此 您将权重设置为1到
one and then you just set your scale to
一个 然后您只需将刻度设置为
whatever it is you want um and I'm also
不管你想要什么 嗯 我也
going to do it for my sprinkles so I'm
为了我的喷雾而做所以我
just going to click on one of my
只需点击我的其中一个
sprinkles
洒水
and yeah right in here for the
是的 就在这里 为了
subsurface I'll just do the same thing
在地下 我会做同样的事情
set the weight as one these radiuses to
将权重设置为这些半径的1
one and then I'll use a really low value
1 然后我将使用一个非常低的值
here like let's go
在这里 我们走吧
two and now you can see because these
两个 现在你可以看到 因为这些
sprinkles are yeah it's like icing right
洒水是的 就像糖霜一样 对吧
it's just the exact same thing um yeah
就是一模一样的东西 嗯 对
we want some of the light to pass
我们想要一些光线通过
through it and we don't actually have to
通过它 我们实际上不必
bother setting up that um that color
费心地设置那个 那个颜色
ramp system for the metal because Metals
金属坡道系统 因为金属
automatically that Shader when you set
设置时自动启用该着色器
it to one it means it's going to cancel
它是1 这意味着它将取消
any subsurface scattering that would
任何地下散射都会
have appeared there so we don't have to
已经出现在那里 所以我们不必
bother with it the subsurface is not
麻烦了 地下并不是
going to happen on Metals um but you can
会发生在金属上 嗯 但你可以
see it starts to feel a lot softer a lot
看 它开始感觉柔和多了
um I don't know more pleasing more
嗯 我不知道更令人愉快的事了
delicious looking like real food because
美味看起来像真正的食物 因为
that's really one of the telltale signs
这真的是一个很明显的迹象
of food is subsurface scattering awesome
食物的地下散布令人惊叹
so in the next part we're going to start
所以在下一部分 我们将从
really building out the scene what I
我真的创造了这样的场景
want to do though at the end of this
想要在这结束时做些什么
video I want to give you some homework
视频我想给你布置一些作业
and that is to try to model this plate
那就是试着对这个盘子进行建模
now we're going to do it actually in the
现在我们要在
next part but it's simple enough and
下一部分 但它很简单
it's actually possible to use all the
实际上可以使用所有
tools that I've mentioned in this uh
我在这里提到的工具呃
this series so far to model this
到目前为止 这个系列对这个进行了建模
yourself now the reason I I'm trying to
现在你自己就是我努力的原因
give this as homework is that once this
把这个作为家庭作业是一旦这个
tutorial finishes that's how it's going
教程结束就是这样进行的
to be you're going to have to try to
要成为你必须尝试
solve problems on the fly so it
即时解决问题
definitely helps solidify learning if
如果
you can try to apply it um by yourself
你可以尝试一下自己应用一下
so have a go it doesn't matter if you
所以尝试一下 如果你
get stuck or you fail at it terribly
陷入困境或者你失败得很严重
because you can just click the next part
因为你可以点击下一部分
and see how it's done but have a go at
看看是如何做到的 但尝试一下
it now um because then you'll start to
现在嗯 因为那时你就会开始
you you'll just retain the information a
你只需要保留信息
lot better anyways go ahead click here
无论如何都好得多 继续点击这里
and uh and see how we build the rest of
呃 看看我们如何建造其余的
the scene and build that plate
场景并构建该板块